Guide to the J. Walter Thompson Company. Frankfurt Office. Burkhard Schwarz papers, 1970-1990 RL.00700
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
J. Walter Thompson Company. Frankfurt Office. Burkhard Schwarz papers
1970-1990
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
J. Walter Thompson Company. Frankfurt Office
RL.00700
22.7 Linear Feet
22.7 linear feet.
Founded in 1864, the J. Walter Thompson Company (JWT) is one of the oldest and largest enduring advertising agencies in the United States. It is headquartered in New York. Burkhard Schwarz was an advertising executive who served as Managing Director of JWT's Frankfurt Office from 1977-1989. Collection includes correspondence, financial summaries, client files, speeches, meeting minutes and other materials, planning and research reports, and new business presentations. Companies represented include Bacardi, Burger King, DeBeers, Ford, Hill & Knowlton, Jacobs, Kodak, Nestle, Philips, Sunlicht and Unilever. Materials are in German and English. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to researchers.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. There may be a 48-hour delay in obtaining these materials.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The J. Walter Thompson Company. Frankfurt Office. Burkhard Schwarz papers was received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a transfer in 1996.
Historical Note
1936: Born, Berlin. 1955-1958: Apprentice, Edeka Grosseinkauf. 1958-1959: Trainee, Schroder & Schyler. 1959-1960: Marketing Manager, Ph. de Rothschild.
JWT career: 1960-1962 Traffic Dept.; 1963 Account Representative, Frankfurt; 1964-1966 Amsterdam; 1967-1970 Account Representative, Account Supervisor, Vienna; 1971 Account Director, Managing Supervisor, Frankfurt; 1977 Senior Vice President, Managing Director, Frankfurt; 1989 retired from JWT.
Collection Overview
Correspondence, financial summaries, client files, speeches, meeting minutes and other materials, planning and research reports, and new business presentations. Companies represented include Bacardi, Burger King, DeBeers, Ford, Hill & Knowlton, Jacobs, Kodak, Nestle, Philips, Sunlicht and Unilever. Materials are in German and English. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising &, and Marketing History.
Advertising agencies -- Germany; Advertising agencies; Advertising -- Management; Advertising executives; Advertising -- History; Hill and Knowlton, Inc.; De Beers Consolidated Mines; Eastman Kodak Company; Burger King Corporation; Schwarz, Burkhard; Nestlé; Kellogg Company; John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History; J. Walter Thompson Company; J. Walter Thompson Company. Frankfurt Office
- General Files, 1971-1990; 1
  - 3 Year Plan, 1983-1987; 3 folders (Box 1)
  - 3-Years Plan: "Where are we?", 1980-1982; 3 folders (Box 1)
  - Acquisitions, 1988-1989 (Box 1)
  - Acquisitions, Mergers; Proposal Dusseldorf; Future Speech, 1985-1990; 4 folders (Box 1)
  - Agency Compensation, 1970s-1985 (Box 1)
  - Allgemein [General], 1976; 4 folders (Box 1)
  - Andere [Other] Offices, 1978-1987; 3 folders (Box 1)
  - Annual Management Assessment, 1976-1980; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Annual Management Assessment, 1976-1980; 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Annual Management Assessment, 1980-1981; 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Basis Research, 1981-1987; 4 folders (Box 2)
  - Basis, H&K, Conquest, Business World, T&A, 1986-1990; 2 folders (Box 2)
  - CLK [Craton Lodge and Knight], 1986-1988 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, 1980 (Box 2)
  - Davos [Symposium], 1979-1986; 5 folders (Box 2)
  - Davos [World Economic Forum], 1986-1989; 3 folders (Box 2)
  - Direct Marketing, 1984-1985; 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Dusseldorf, 1985-1989; 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Dusseldorf, 1985-1989 (Box 3)
  - Dusseldorf Bürogründung / Opening, 1982-1983; 2 folders (Box 3)
  - EMG [European Managers Group], 1987-1988; 3 folders (Box 3)
  - EMG [European Managers Group] "1992 Group", 1989; 2 folders (Box 3)
  - EMM [European Managers Meeting], 1977-1987; 4 folders (Box 3)
  - EMM [European Managers Meeting], 1983; 3 folders (Box 3)
  - EPCOT [World Advertising Forum], 1984; 4 folders (Box 3)
  - EROC [European Regional Operating Committee Meeting], 1986; 3 folders (Box 3)
  - EROC [European Regional Operating Committee Meeting], 1986; 4 folders (Box 4)
  - Euro-Advertising, 1978-1985; 3 folders (Box 4)
  - Executive Board, AMG, OMG, 1986-1987 (Box 4)
  - Finance, 1986-1987; 8 folders (Box 4)
  - Finanzen [Finances], 1977-1982; 4 folders (Box 4)
  - Finanzen, Verträge [Finances, Contracts], 1983-1984; 3 folders (Box 4)
  - GWA--Korrespondenz [Correspondence], 1985-1986; 9 folders (Box 5)
  - GWA: Sitzungen, Protokolle [Meetings, Minutes], 1987-1989; 6 folders (Box 5)
  - Hamburg, 1981-1987; 5 folders (Box 5)
  - Hamburg Kunden [Clients], NB [New Business], 1980-1988; 2 folders (Box 5)
  - Hamburg Kunden [Clients], NB [New Business], 1980-1988; 2 folders (Box 6)
  - Hamburg, JWT Direct, Dusseldorf, WPP, 1983-1989; 5 folders (Box 6)
  - H. F. Peters, 1981-1988; 2 folders (Box 6)
  - Hill and Knowlton [H&K], 1980-1984; 3 folders (Box 6)
  - JWT Allgemein [General Information], 1974-1990; 8 folders (Box 6)
  - JWT Direct, 1985-1988; 3 folders (Box 6)
  - JWT Directories, 1980-1989 (Box 7)
  - JWT Offices, Correspondence, A-Z, 1978; 4 folders (Box 7)
  - Korrespondenz Allgemein [General Correspondence], 1981-1990; 9 folders (Box 7)
  - London Office, 1979-1984; 7 folders (Box 7)
  - London Office, 1985-1988; 7 folders (Box 8)
  - Managers Monthly Assessment [MMA], 1979-1988; 14 folders (Box 8)
  - Managers Monthly Assessment [MMA], 1988; 2 folders (Box 9)
  - Markenplan VRBA, 1980-1981; 2 folders (Box 9)
  - Markenplan: Verträge [Contracts], 1981; 2 folders (Box 9)
  - Memoranda/Haus-Mitteilungen, 1977-1982; 4 folders (Box 9)
  - Memos, 1984-1987; 3 folders (Box 9)
  - New York Office, 1979-1980s; 8 folders (Box 9)
  - New York [Correspondence], 1987-1988; 3 folders (Box 10)
  - New York and Other Offices, 1989; 3 folders (Box 10)
  - OC (Operating Committee), GL, Directors Meeting, Creative Planboards, 1977-1985; 4 folders (Box 10)
  - Personal (Personnel) general files, 1985-1989; 3 folders (Box 10)
  - Personal (Personnel) A-Z, Allgemein, Bewerbung [General and Employment Applications], 1973-1985; 6 folders (Box 10)
  - P [Personnel?]: Allgemein, Organisation, Etat, Bewerbung [General, Organization, Budget, Employment Application(s)], 1975-1976; 2 folders (Box 10)
  - P [Personnel?]: Allgemein, Organisation, Etat, Bewerbung [General, Organization, Budget, Employment Application(s)], 1975-1976; 2 folders (Box 11)
  - Presse [Media], 1985; 3 folders (Box 11)
  - Privat, Management Wechsel [Personal, Change in Management], 1971-1977; 3 folders (Box 11)
  - Releases, Newsletter, 1979-1986; 4 folders (Box 11)
  - Schotten Meetings, 1980-1981; 3 folders (Box 11)
  - Seminare [Seminars], 1971-1975; 2 folders (Box 11)
  - T&A; Deltakos, 1978-1988; 3 folders (Box 11)
  - Umstrukturierung [Restructuring], 1986; 2 folders (Box 11)
  - Vorträge--Allgemein [Lectures/Speeches--General], 1977 (Box 11)
  - Vorträge--Allgemein [Lectures/Speeches--General], 1977-1989; 14 folders (Box 12)
  - Vorträge [Lectures/Speeches]: allg. [gen.], Sunlicht, 1976-1978; 4 folders (Box 12)
  - Wien [Vienna], 1980-1987; 3 folders (Box 12)
  - Wien [Vienna], 1980-1989; 5 folders (Box 13)
  - Wien [Vienna]: 3-Years Plan, Finance, Personal, Pension / Versicherung [Insurance], Taxes, 1983-1987; 3 folders (Box 13)
  - Wien [Vienna], [Tiefenbrunner], 1984-1986; 3 folders (Box 13)
  - WPP, 1986-1988; 3 folders (Box 13)
  - Zurich bis 1988, 1979-1988; 4 folders (Box 13)
- Account Files, 1970-1990; 2
  - Bacardi, 1985-1988; 5 folders (Box 13)
  - Burger King, 1983-1986 (Box 14)
  - Burger King, Ford, Sunlicht, Elida, 1970-1983; 4 folders (Box 14)
  - Client Retention, 1981-1986; 5 folders (Box 14)
  - Client Retention [includes Christian Grupe files], 1986-1989; 3 folders (Box 14)
  - DeBeers, 1984-1990; 9 folders (Box 14)
  - DeBeers, Kellogg, 1970-1983; 2 folders (Box 14)
  - DeBeers, Kellogg, 1970-1983 (Box 15)
  - FLACHGLAS, GEFA, 1980-1989 (Box 15)
  - Ford, 1985-1986; 9 folders (Box 15)
  - Ford Client Retention, 1979-1986 (Box 15)
  - Ford Korrespondenz [Correspondence], 1983-1988; 4 folders (Box 15)
  - Jacobs, 1984-1987; 5 folders (Box 15)
  - Jacobs, 1988-1989; 4 folders (Box 16)
  - Kellogg, 1984-1990; 11 folders (Box 16)
  - Kodak, 1971; 3 folders (Box 16)
  - Kodak [Notebooks of Christian Grupe], 1980-1989; 4 folders (Box 16)
  - Kunden [Clients], 1970s-1987; 21 folders (Box 17)
  - Kunden [Clients], 1986-1989; 16 folders (Box 18)
  - Lever GMBH, 1982-1987; 3 folders (Box 18)
  - Nestlé, 1980-1987; 5 folders (Box 18)
  - Nestlé, 1985-1987; 4 folders (Box 19)
  - Philips, 1979-1989; 4 folders (Box 19)
  - Pizza Hut, 1987-1988 (Box 19)
  - Promotions, 1983-1984; 2 folders (Box 19)
  - Sunlicht Coordination, 1973-1977; 3 folders (Box 19)
  - Unilever, Elida, 1983-1989; 4 folders (Box 19)
- New Business Files, 1978-1989; 3
  - A-Z, 1987; 5 folders (Box 19)
  - A-Z, 1987-1989; 5 folders (Box 20)
  - Future, 1980; 2 folders (Box 20)
  - International [New Business], 1987-1989; 3 folders (Box 20)
  - Klausurtagung Niederwald [Private Meeting], 1985; 2 folders (Box 20)
  - Kontakte [New Business Contacts], A-Z, 1988-1989; 7 folders (Box 20)
  - Pharma-Präsentationen [Pharmaceutical Presentations], 1978-1984; 4 folders (Box 20)
  - Pharma-Präsentationen [Pharmaceutical Presentations], 1978-1984 (Box 21)
  - Protokolle [New Business Minutes], 1987; 4 folders (Box 21)
  - S [Workshop], 1987-1989; 4 folders (Box 21)